{
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZop" : {
    "back" : "*Tokaji* harvests are separated into three categories:\n\n* *Aszú* - individual rotten grapes when *botrytis* is widespread\n* *Szamorodni* - entire bunch of grapes when only a few berries are affected by *botrytis*\n* and normal healthy grapes.",
    "front" : "How do pickers categorize grapes for *Tokaji*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "new",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tag" : ["hu", "varietals", "law", "tokaji"]
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZor" : {
    "back" : "* non-botrytis dry wines\n* *Tokaji Szamorodni* - dry (száraz) or sweet (édes)\n* *Tokaji Aszu*\n* *Aszú Eszencia*\n* *Tokaji Eszencia* (essence or nectar)\n* mordern style sweet wines",
    "front" : "List the *Tokaji* styles.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "new",
    "status" : "new",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tag" : ["hu", "winestyle", "tokaji", "sweet_wine"]
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZot" : {
    "back" : "1. *Tokaji Aszú* starts with a base wine from healthy grapes\n2. Aszu berries are macerated in the base wine, either during or after fermentation, for up to 36 hours\n3. mixture is pressed and the wine is matured for a minimum of three years, two of which must be in oak barrels",
    "front" : "How is *Tokaji Aszú* produced?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tag" : ["hu", "viniculture", "tokaji", "sweet_wine"]
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZov" : {
    "back" : "Minimum of 180 g/L residual sugar is required for *Aszú Eszencia.\n",
    "front" : "How much residual sugar is required for an *Aszú Eszencia*? ",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tag" : ["hu", "law", "tokaji", "sweet_wine"]
  },
  "-L576FESNrFBSwq-YHAu" : {
    "back" : "*Aszú* wines, including *Aszú Eszencia* have a noticeable *oxidative* character.\n\nTypical *Aszú* wines is *deep amber*, *high acidity*, have *intense aromas*, and have flavours of *orange marmalade*, *apricots*, and *honey*.\n\nBest wines have complex layers of *rye*, *bread*, *smoke*, *coffee*, and *caramel*.",
    "front" : "Describe the characteristics of *Aszú* wines.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tag" : ["hu", "winestyle", "tokaji", "sweet_wine"]
  },
  "-L576FESNrFBSwq-YHAw" : {
    "back" : "| 3 *puttonyos* | 60 g/L | \n| 4 *puttonyos | 90 g/L | \n| 5 *puttonyos | 120 g/L | | 6 *puttonyos | 150 g/L | ",
    "front" : "List the legal minimum levels of residual sugar for *Tokaji Aszú*.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tag" : ["hu", "law", "tokaji", "sweet_wine"]
  },
  "11111" : {
    "back" : "450 g/L",
    "front" : "What is the minimum residual sugar level required for *Tokaji Eszencia*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tag" : ["hu", "law", "tokaji", "sweet_wine"]
  },
  "11112" : {
    "back" : "*Tokaji Eszencia* is made from the free-run juice of the *aszú berries*, where the must is so sweet that it could take years to ferment and still remain very low in alcohol (less than 5% abv).\n\nThe sweetness is balanced by very high acidity and highly concentrated flavours.\n\n*Eszencia* wines can mature and retain its freshness for a century or more.",
    "front" : "What factors contribute to *Tokaji Eszencia* distinct style?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tag" : ["hu", "winestyle", "tokaji", "sweet_wine"]
  },
  "11117" : {
    "back" : "*Tokaji Szamorodni* are made from grapes harvested as *Szamorodni* that can be dry (száraz) or sweet (édes) depending on the amount of noble rot. Hence even dry wines will show hints of noble rot characteristics.\n\nWines must be aged in cask for minimum of one year and be two years old before release.\n\nFor dry wines, casks are not completely filled to enable *flor*-like yeast to form on the wine and developers a character similar to a *Fino Sherry*.",
    "front" : "How are *Tokaji Szamorodni* wines made?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tag" : ["hu", "viniculture", "tokaji"]
  },
  "11122" : {
    "back" : "__Hungary__ has a *continental* climate with a long, warm summer and autumn ripening season.\n\nSome sites there is sufficient early morning humidity to regularly promote noble rot.",
    "front" : "What is __Hungary's__ growing climate?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tag" : ["hu", "climate"]
  },

  "11113" : {
    "back" : "*Egri Bikavér*, also known as *Bull's Blood*, is a full-bodied dry red wine blend, usually anchored by the *Kékfrankos grape*.\n\nModern *Egri Bikavér* is usually light in tannins and body.",
    "front" : "What is an *Egri Bikavér*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "tag" : ["hu", "winestyle"]
  },
  "11114" : {
    "back" : "Officially *Egri Bikavér* must contain at least three of the following 13 grapes:\n\n
*Bíbor kadarka*, *Blauburger*, *Cabernet Franc*, *Cabernet Sauvignon*, *Kadarka*, *Kékfrankos*, *Kékoportó*, *Menoire*, *Merlot*, *Pinot Noir*, *Syrah*, *Turán*, *Zweigelt*",
    "front" : "What grape varieties are used for *Egri Bikavér*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "tag" : ["hu", "law", "varietals"]
  },
  "11115" : {
    "back" : "22",
    "front" : "How many vineyard areas are there in __Hungary__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "tag" : ["hu", "law"]
  },
  "11116" : {
    "back" : "Main varieties in __Tokaj__:\n\n* *Furmint*\n* Hárslevelhü*\n* *Sárga Muscotály*",
    "front" : "What are the main grape varieties grown in __Tokaj__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "tag" : ["hu", "varietals", "tokaji"]
  },
  "11118" : {
    "back" : "*Sárga Muscotály* (*Muscat Blanc à Petits Grains*) is aromatic and have flavours of *orange blossom*.\n\n*Olasz Rizling* (*Welschriesling*) is crisp, light, with an aftertaste of *bitter almonds*.",
    "front" : "What are the characteristics of *Sárga Muscotály* and *Olasz Rizling*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "tag" : ["hu", "varietals"]
  },
  "11119" : {
    "back" : "*Kékfrankos*",
    "front" : "What is the __Hungarian__ name for *Blaufränkisch*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "tag" : ["hu", "varietals", "blaufrankisch"]
  },
  "11120" : {
    "back" : "*Kékfrankos*\n\nlight, peppery, purple-coloured, high acidity",
    "front" : "What are the characteristics of *Kékfrankos*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "tag" : ["hu", "varietals"]
  },
  "11121" : {
    "back" : "*Zweigelt* is a cross between *Kékfrankos* and *St Laurent*",
    "front" : "What are the parent grapes of *Zweigelt*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "tag" : ["hu", "varietals", "zweigelt"]
  },

  "gr0001" : {
    "front" : "What is special about the PGI *Oenoi Onomasias Kata Paradosi/Appellation Traditionnelle (OKP)*?",
    "back" : "OKP is unlike all other PGIs as it deals with a style of wine instead of a geographic location.\n\nIt is used to accommodate the wine style *Retsina* that can be made anywhere in __Greece__.",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "law"]
  },
  "gr0002" : {
    "front" : "What grape varieties are used to make *Retsina*?",
    "back" : "*Savatino* and *Roditis* grapes",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "winestyle", "varietals"]
  },
  "gr0003" : {
    "front" : "How many *PDO* regions are there in __Greece__?",
    "back" : "There are 33 *PDOs* in Greece:\n\n* 8 *Oenoi Onomasias Proelefseos Elenhomeni/Appellation d'Origine Contrôlée (OPE)\n* 25 *Oenoi Onomasias Proelefseos Anoteras Poiotitas/Appellation d'Origine de Qualité Supérieure (OPAP)*",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "law" ]
  },
  "gr0004" : {
    "front" : "What is the biggest factor to *Retsina's* distinctive character?",
    "back" : "*Pine resin*\n\nPine resin from local trees is added to the wine when it is young and removed at the first racking. This is what gives *Retsina* it's distinctive profile.",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "winestyle"]
  },

  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZol" : {
    "back" : "Dry and sweet white wines principally made from *Assyrtiko*. ",
    "front" : "What grape varieties are used for *Santorini OPAP*?",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "law", "varietals" ]
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZon" : {
    "back" : "Red wines, made exclusively from *Agiorgitiko*.",
    "front" : "What grape varieties are used for *Nemea OPAP*?",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "law", "nemea", "varietals" ]
  },
  "gr0005" : {
    "back" : "Red wines, made exclusively from *Xinomavro*.",
    "front" : "What grape varieties are used for *Naoussa OPAP*?",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "law", "naoussa", "varietals", "xenomavro" ]
  },
  "gr0006" : {
    "front" : "Describe a typical *Naoussa OPAP* wine.",
    "back" : "*Naossa OPAP* is made from *Xinomavro* - a variety similar to *Nebbiolo*.\n\nThey are typically medium coloured red wines high in tannins and acidity, and lack significant fresh fruit even in their youth.\n\nLike *Nebbiolo*, they can develop complex spice and earthy aromas with age.",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "winestyle", "naoussa", "nebbiolo", "xenomavro"]
  },
  "gr0007" : {
    "back" : "*Nemea OPAP* vineyards are spread between 230 to 900m above sea level.\n\nAlthough the best fruits come from the middle of this range.",
    "front" : "What elevation are *Nemea OPAP* vineyards at?",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "law", "nemea", "varietals", "xenomavro" ]
  },
  "gr0008" : {
    "front" : "How does altitude affect *Nemea OPAP* wines?",
    "back" : "* hotter lower slopes produces overtly jammy and fruity wines for early consumption\n* cooler higher slopes have higher acidity and less fine tannins",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "winestyle", "nemea" ]
  },
  "gr0009" : {
    "front" : "What are the typical characteristics of *Nemea OPAP* wines?",
    "back" : "* deep ruby colour\n* high levels of rounded tannins\n* moderate to low acidity\n* sweet spice and red fruit flavours\n* great with oak influences",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "winestyle", "nemea" ]
  },
  "gr0010" : {
    "front" : "What wine style is *Santorini OPAP* known for?",
    "back" : "*Santorini OPAP* made its reputation with dry and sweet wines made from *Assyrtiko*.",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "winestyle", "assyrtiko", "santorini" ]
  },
  "gr0011" : {
    "front" : "What are sweet wines from *Santorini OPAP* called?",
    "back" : "*Vinsanto*",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "winestyle", "assyrtiko", "santorini", "sweet_wine" ]
  },
  "gr0012" : {
    "front" : "How does wind in *Santorini* affect winestyle?",
    "back" : "Winds at *Santorini* are so strong that photosynthesis can stop. This slows ripening and so acid levels remain high.\nGrapes are also dehydrated on the vine, concentrating sugar levels, thereby increasing alcohol levels.",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "winestyle", "assyrtiko", "santorini" ]
  },
  "gr0013" : {
    "front" : "What are some characteristics of older *Vinsantos*?",
    "back" : "Older *Vinsantos* show marked *oxidative* characters of *caramel* and *nuts*",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "winestyle", "assyrtiko", "santorini", "sweet_wine" ]
  },
  "gr0014" : {
    "front" : "Describe a dry *Assyrtiko* from __Santorini__.",
    "back" : "* highly concentrated\n* perfumed\n* high in acid and alcohol",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "winestyle", "assyrtiko", "santorini" ]
  },
  "gr0015" : {
    "back" : "85% of the grapes must be *Moschofilero*.",
    "front" : "What grape varieties are used for *Mantinia OPAP*?",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "law", "mantinia", "varietals", "moschofilero" ]
  },
  "gr0016" : {
    "front" : "What grape variety is *Moschofilero* similar to?",
    "back" : "*Moschofilero* has an aromatic character and intensity similar to *Muscat* or *Gewurztraminer*",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "varietals", "muscat", "gewurztraminer" ]
  },
  "gr0017" : {
    "front" : "Describe a dry *Moschofilero*.",
    "back" : "* light bodied\n* high acidity\n* medium alcohol\n* intense pure aromas similar to *Muscat* or *Gewurztraminer*",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "winestyle"]
  },
  "gr0018" : {
    "front" : "How do __Santorini__ grape growers protect the fruit from the areas high winds?",
    "back" : "__Santorini__ grape growers use a unique training method:\n\nPermanent wood is trained very low and into a basket shape, with the fruit growing on the inside.",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "viticulture", "santorini" ]
  },
  "gr0019" : {
    "front" : "What factors contribute to the intense labour involved in grape growing in __Greece__?",
    "back" : "__Greece__ has a mountainous terrain with predominantly small holdings. Most vineyards are *spur pruned* and *head trained*.\n\nThese factors make it extremely difficult for mechanical harvesting in __Greece__.",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["gr", "terroir", "viticulture" ]
  },


}
